If you recall from earlier in the lesson,
如果你还记得前面课程的内容
writing Modular Code is a necessary practice in software development,
编写模块化代码是软件开发中的必要实践
where you split your program into logical functions and modules.
将程序拆分为逻辑性的函数和模块
Let's go over some guidelines to help you with this.
下面通过一些提示指南来帮助理解
First, Don't Repeat Yourself,
首先 不要重复自己
modularization allows you to reuse parts of your code.
模块化使你可以复用部分代码
Let's go back to the example earlier on grading test scores.
让我们回到之前关于测试分数的例子
Here, we have a list of test scores that we curve in three different ways,
在这里 我们有一个测试分数列表 后面以三种不同的方式变换数值
say you're an educator who gave out a test that was too
假设你是一名教育工作者 出了一次很难的测试题
difficult or gave a question that was a little unfair.
或提出的问题有点不公平
So, you decide to figure out a way to boost your students' scores.
所以你决定找出一种抬高学生成绩的方法
For the first two methods,
前两种方法
out of flat curve a 5 points to each score and 10 points to each score.
是比较线性的变换 分别为每个分数提高 5 分和 10 分
In the third method,
在第三种方法中
we apply a square root curve,
应用平方根变换
where we find the square root of each score,
得出每个分数的平方根
and multiply it by 10.
然后乘以 10
Right now, it's difficult to understand what
现在很难理解这段代码的作用
this code is for and looks pretty repetitive.
并且看起来非常重复
This is an example of spaghetti code,
这是 "面条式代码" 的示例
which is common in data scientists and is not something we want to follow.
在数据科学家中很常见 但并不是我们想要遵循的
Let's use the tips we learned earlier on writing
让我们应用编写整洁代码课程中学到的技巧
clean code and improve this with better naming and readable functions.
使用更好的命名和可读的函数来优化这段代码
We can represent this list of scores better with something descriptive,
可以用具有描述性的名称来表示这个分数列表
like test scores, and use numpy to get the mean of each list.
比如 test_scores 然后使用 numpy 来获得每个列表的均值
We can also use list comprehensions to make this more concise and readable,
还可以使用列表推导式 使代码更精炼和可读
and use more descriptive names for the score and resulting list,
为分数和结果列表使用更具有描述性的名称
our code is clear now,
我们的代码现在很清晰了
but still needs more refactoring.
但仍需要更多的重构
First of all, these lines applying a flat curve of 5 and 10 look awfully similar.
首先 应用 5 和 10 线性变换的代码行看起来非常相似
We can generalize this in one function and we can also
我们可以将其概括为一个函数 还可以
consolidate all of these print statements into a four loop.
将这些打印语句整合为一个 for 循环
This actually demonstrates the next tip,
这实际上展示了下一个提示
abstract that logic to improve readability.
抽象出逻辑来提高可读性
Notice how abstracting out code into a function not only makes it less repetitive,
我们注意到 将代码抽象为函数 不仅使其重复性降低
but also improves the readability with descriptive function names.
也因描述性的函数名 提高了代码可读性
You can easily guess that this line is applying a flat curve of 5 on the
可以很容易地猜到 这行代码是对测试成绩应用 5 的线性变换
test scores list and that this line is doing the same thing with 10,
这一行是用 10 来做相同的变换
and this line applies a different curve using square root and with this four loop
这一行是使用平方根变换成绩曲线 下面使用 for 循环后
not only are we removing repeated lines of
我们不仅删除了重复的代码行
code it's also easier to follow what's happening,
也更容易理解代码的功能
we're clearly iterating through four lists and printing the mean of each.
显然 这是在遍历四个列表 然后打印每个列表的均值
Note that although your code can become more
请注意 尽管将逻辑抽象为函数
readable when you abstract out logic into functions,
可以使代码可读性更高
it's possible to over-engineer this and have way too many functions.
但很可能会过度设计 最终拥有太多函数
So, use your judgment,
所以 你需要判断
this leads us to the next tip.
这引出了我们的下一个提示
Minimize the number of entities like functions, classes, and modules.
函数、类和模块等实体的数量最小化
There are trade-offs to having function calls instead of in-line logic.
函数调用还是内联逻辑需要权衡
If you've broken up your code into an unnecessary amount of functions and modules,
如果将代码分解为很多不必要的函数和模块
you'll have to jump around everywhere.
你就必须到处跳
If you want to view the implementation details
如果要查看某个小功能的实现详情
for something that may be too small to be worth it,
跳来跳去查看可能并不值得
it's kind of the same as naming variables.
这与命名变量时的考虑有些类似
A longer variable name doesn't necessarily equate to increased readability,
较长的变量名不一定等同于提高可读性
the same way creating more modules doesn't
创建更多模块同样也不会
necessarily result in effective modularization.
必然导致有效的模块化
Moving on to the next tip,
继续下一个提示
make sure that each function you write,
确保你写的每个函数
is focused on doing one thing,
专注于做一件事
for example you wouldn't want something like this,
例如 你不会想要这样的代码
this is the same thing we had before except now
这与之前的示例相似
each curve function also prints the mean in addition to returning the adjusted list.
只是每个变换函数还会打印调整后分数列表的均值
Avoid having unnecessary side effects and functions and keep them focused.
要避免在函数中产生不必要的副作用 使它们保持专注
Even if you rename them this way to indicate that they're printing the mean,
即使你以这种方式重命名函数 表明会打印均值
the functions are still doing multiple things and
这些函数仍然是在做多件事
become more difficult to generalize and reuse.
变得更难以概括和复用
Generally, if there's an and in your function name, consider refactoring.
通常 如果你的函数名中包含 and 请考虑重构
Another tip is that arbitrary variable names can be more effective in certain functions.
另一个提示是 任意变量名在某些函数中可能更有效
Notice that in these functions,
注意 在这些函数中
we broke some rules on using descriptive variable names.
我们打破了使用描述性变量名的规则
This is because arbitrary variable names in general functions such as this,
这是因为像这样的一般函数中的任意变量名
can actually make the code more readable.
实际上可以使代码更具可读性
Flat curve doesn't actually have to be for test scores,
线性变换实际上不一定针对测试得分
it can be used on any iterable that you want to curve up by a certain integer.
它可以用于任何想要增加某个整数值的迭代
While we're on the topic of writing simple and focused functions,
我们的主题是撰写简单而专注的函数
another useful tip is to make sure that you
另一个有用的提示是
use no more than three arguments when possible.
尽可能不超过三个参数
Of course, this is not a hard rule and there are
当然 这不是一个硬性规则
times it's more appropriate to use many parameters,
有时确实多个参数更加恰当
but in the vast majority of cases,
但在绝大多数情况下
it's more effective to use fewer arguments.
使用较少的参数更高效
Remember, we are modularizing to
请记住 我们正在模块化
simplify our code and make it more efficient to work with.
以简化代码并使其更有效地使用
If your function has a lot of parameters,
如果你的函数有很多参数
you may want to rethink how you're splitting this up.
可能需要重新考虑如何拆分它
With this small example,
通过这个小例子
you saw how functions can be used to abstract out parts of
你看到了如何使用函数来抽象出程序的各个部分
a program to make it more readable, clear, and reusable.
使其更可读、清晰和可复用
This becomes more essential,
随着算法越来越复杂
the more complex your algorithms are,
这变得越来越重要
especially in data science work.
特别是在数据科学工作中